<!-- $Id: preface.xml,v 1.2 2003/10/16 13:12:03 zas Exp $ -->

<preface id="foreword"><title> Foreword </title>
	
<?dbhtml filename="preface.html"?>

<para>

	ELinks is lacking proper documentation. For a long time the only real
	documentation available besides the man pages has been the now old
	<ulink url="http://links.sourceforge.net/docs/manual-0.90-en/"> Links
	User Reference Manual</ulink> written by Cliff Cunnington
	(<email>cliff@users.sf.net</email>).  This document an attempt at
	providing a manual for ELinks users. You will find some of it is
	derived from the before mentioned Links manual.  Thanks to Cliff for
	the work he has made available.

</para>

<bridgehead> Status of this document </bridgehead>
<para>

	This is version &version; of the book. It is a work in progress.
	Contributions are very welcome. Please consider to contribute if you
	see something missing. See how to contribute below.

</para>

<bridgehead> Available formats </bridgehead>
<para>

	The ELinks book is available in the following formats:

</para>
<variablelist>
	<varlistentry><term>HTML:</term>
	<listitem><para>

	<ulink url="http://elinks.or.cz/documentation/manual/elinks-manual.html/"></ulink>

	</para></listitem>
	</varlistentry>
</variablelist>
<para>

	There can exist different versions of the book. But the the newest
	version will always be available at <ulink
	url="http://elinks.or.cz/documentation/book">the book's page</ulink>
	at the ELinks homepage.

</para>

<bridgehead id="how-to-contribute">How to contribute</bridgehead>
<para>

	This book is written by ELinks users that wants to help other users.
	If you want to help us make the best ELinks book possible your
	contribution will be very welcome.

</para>
<para>

	Any help is useful; from people providing chapters of various features
	to people fixing bad grammar or typos. If you have suggestions for a
	new chapter or how to improve an existing one we would be happy to
	hear from you.

</para>
<para>

	Further info about how to contribute can be found on the manuals
	homepage: <ulink url="http://elinks.or.cz/documentation/manual">
	http://elinks.or.cz/documentation/manual</ulink>.

</para>
</preface>
