<!-- $Id -->

<chapter id="bookmarks"><title> The Ultimate Bookmarks Guide </title>
	
<?dbhtml filename="bookmarks.html"?>

<para>

	Glad to see you again, mortal. Now, we are going to learn about
	bookmarks - how to use them, how to maintain them, and also something
	more about the file formats and maybe even about the code structure
	later. But don't fear, we won't burden you with it, just stop reading
	when you will know enough already.

</para>
<para>

	In order to read this, you need some common sense, ability to start
	ELinks and some idea about what's a web document, URL address and
	knowledge like that.

</para>
<para>

	If we will ever mention some keys here, please note that you can rebind
	almost any action to another key which you like more - then you must
	obviously imagine your own key in place of that. Below, we will list
	all actions, options and so on, related to bookmarks. We won't tell you
	how to rebind the keys, though; this will be described in another
	section.

</para>

<sect1><title> The Bookmark Manager </title>
<para>

	Basically, almost everything is going on in so-called bookmark manager.
	That's special dialog window, which contains listing of all bookmarks
	you ever told ELinks to remember and it lets you to do with them
	anything you would ever want to do with them.

</para>
<para>

	You launch the bookmark manager by pressing the 's' key in standby
	(standard) mode. You should see a big empty space (bookmarks will
	slowly appear there as you will add them) and couple of buttons
	shriveling at the bottom. So, as a start, move with the right (or left,
	both will do) arrow to the button "Add bookmark" and fill in the input
	fields it will offer to you. I mean, you can type something like
	<userinput>ELinks homepage</userinput> to the first field, then move
	down by ie.  the down arrow and fill
	<userinput>http://elinks.or.cz/</userinput> to the second field. Then,
	bravely press enter and watch the bookmark popping up at the top of the
	vast area reserved for bookmarks.

</para>
<para>

	Repeat this step few times. Now, you can move between bookmarks by the
	up and down arrow, jump to the location any of them points to by the
	Goto button, change it by the Edit button, delete it with the Delete
	button and so on.. When you'll become bored, press the escape button
	and you're free again!

</para>
</sect1>

<sect1><title> The Ancient Forests </title>
<para>

	It's not very convenient to have all the bookmarks mixed up - soon, you
	will get lost in them. Thus, in ELinks you can categorize them to
	various folders, subfolders, subsubfolders and so on, then you can
	expand and back enfold them and so on.

</para>
<para>

	In order to create your first folder, use button "Add folder" and fill
	the first input field. You can safely ignore the URL field, ELinks will
	do the same. *POOF* and you see it - it has that strange [+] or [-]
	thing there. If it has [+] near, it's enfolded, while when it has [-]
	near, it is expanded, while you can change that by pressing the
	spacebar.

</para>
<para>

	In order to add a bookmark into a folder, move on the item of the
	folder (it must be expanded) or onto any bookmark inside of the folder,
	and simply do the usual "Add bookmark" job. You can also move the
	bookmarks around, obviously.  You need to first mark all the bookmarks
	(or even folders) you want to move (using the Insert key, asterisk will
	appear near of all marked bookmarks), and then move to where you want
	to have the stuff moved to, and press the "Move" button.

</para>
</sect1>

<sect1><title> Searching needle in the haycock </title>
<para>

	Of course, you can search in the bookmarks. Just use the
	<guibutton>"Find"</guibutton> button - for convenience, you have
	current document's URL and title pre-filled there, and for convenience
	only up-up-enter-down-down sequence is enough to have the playground
	clean. Then, just fill substring of what you are looking for, and the
	bookmarks will be filtered so that only the matching ones are shown.

</para>
</sect1>
</chapter>
