<!-- $Id: installation.xml,v 1.4 2003/10/19 22:28:26 jonas Exp $ -->

<chapter id="installation"><title> Getting ELinks up and running </title>
	
<?dbhtml filename="installation.html"?>

<para>

	Installing ELinks should be pretty easy on most systems. Below is
	described the hole process of getting the sources, configuring
	the compilation and compiling and installing.

</para>

<sect1><title> Getting the source </title>
<para>

	There are various methods of requiring the source code for ELinks all
	you have to do is find one that suites your need. Basically there are two
	flavors:

<variablelist>

	<varlistentry>
	<term><type>stable</type></term>
	<listitem><para>

		The hopefully rock solid version of ELinks that is well tested
		but not fully up to date. This should be considered if you are
		going to maintain ELinks on systems with lot's of users.

	</para></listitem>
	</varlistentry>

	<varlistentry><term><type>development</type> or <type>unstable</type></term>
	<listitem><para>

		The bleeding edge version of ELinks for the brave ones. This
		should be considered if you want to be up to date or need some
		specific feature.  Also consider this flavor if you want to
		contribute to ELinks by testing it. (This of course requires
		you to mail us.
		See more about this in <xref linkend="bugreporting" />).

	</para></listitem>
	</varlistentry>

</variablelist>

	Whether you prefer <type>stable</type> or <type>development</type>
	there are two methods of getting them.

</para>

<sect2><title> Downloading a tarball </title>
<para>

	Tarballs are good if you do not install/upgrade ELinks very often but
	rather when important fixes or releases have been made announced.
	Tarballs are also the installation form that requires least available
	tools for building the program. More about this in <xref
	linkend="requirements" />.

</para>
<para>

	Tarballs of the various flavors are available from the download page
	at ELinks homepage (see <xref linkend="homepage" />). Besides the various
	releases you can download daily generated CVS snapshots of both the
	<type>stable</type> and <type>development</type> branches.

</para>
</sect2>

<sect2><title> The CVS way </title>
<para>

	If you regularly upgrade your ELinks (using the <type>development</type>)
	flavor you will find getting ELinks the CVS way much more easy. Also this
	way you might save some bandwidth since you wont have to download the
	full package every time.
	
</para>	
<note><para>
	Note that when you are installing directly
	from CVS you will need to have some extra programs installed on your system.
	See <xref linkend="requirements" /> for needed software.
	
</para></note>
<para>

	To checkout the <type>development</type> flavor do the following:

</para>
<screen>
<prompt>%</prompt> <userinput>export CVSROOT=:pserver:anonymous@cvs.elinks.or.cz:/var/cvs/elinks</userinput>
<prompt>%</prompt> <userinput>cvs login</userinput>
<userinput>(empty password)</userinput>
<prompt>%</prompt> <userinput>cvs -z3 co elinks</userinput>
</screen>
<para>

	You can also checkout the latest <type>stable</type> ELinks version
	(note that development in the stable branch is usually more-or-less dead
	nowadays ;-). Just do this:

</para>
<screen>
<prompt>%</prompt> <userinput>export CVSROOT=:pserver:anonymous@cvs.elinks.or.cz:/var/cvs/elinks</userinput>
<prompt>%</prompt> <userinput>cvs login</userinput>
<userinput>(empty password)</userinput>
<prompt>%</prompt> <userinput>cvs -z3 co -rREL_0_4 elinks</userinput>
</screen>
<para>

	Later when you want to update your existing tree to the latest CVS
	version just do:
	
</para>
<screen>
<prompt>%</prompt> <userinput>cvs -z3 update -dP</userinput>
</screen>
</sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1><title> Building and Installing ELinks </title>
<para>

	Much of the info in this section can be found in the
	<filename>INSTALL</filename> file which can be found in the root of the
	ELinks source directory.

</para>
<para>

	The quick guide for the impatient. Issue the following commands from
	the ELinks source directory:

</para>
<screen>
<prompt>%</prompt> <userinput>./configure &amp;&amp; make &amp;&amp; make install</userinput>
</screen>
<para>

	However you might consider to tweak a few compile time options before
	building ELinks. Before we seeing how to do this lets take a look at
	some of the programs and libraries required or recommended that you
	install.

</para>

<sect2 id="requirements"><title> Requirements </title>
<para>

	To successfully install ELinks all that is required is <ulink
	url="http://www.gnu.org/software/make/make.html">GNU make</ulink> and a
	C compiler. If you want to install directly from CVS it is also
	required that <command>automake</command> and
	<command>autoconf</command> is installed on your system.

</para>
</sect2>

<sect2><title> Recommended Libraries </title>
<para>

	To make use of many of ELinks features you will need to have some
	external libraries installed on your system.  It is also recommended to
	have the following libraries installed:
	
</para>
<variablelist>
	<varlistentry><term><ulink url="http://www.lua.org">Lua</ulink></term>
	<listitem><para>

		makes it possible to write plugins using the Elinks - Lua
		interface.

	</para></listitem>
	</varlistentry>

	<varlistentry><term><ulink url="http://www.gzip.org">GNU zip</ulink></term>
	<listitem><para>

		for handling compressed documents both locally and sent from
		server.

	</para></listitem>
	</varlistentry>

	<varlistentry><term><ulink url="http://sources.redhat.com/bzip2">bzip2</ulink></term>
	<listitem><para>

		for handling local compressed documents.

	</para></listitem>
	</varlistentry>

	<varlistentry><term><ulink url="http://www.openssl.org">OpenSSL</ulink>
		or <ulink url="http://www.gnu.org/software/gnutls">GNU TLS</ulink>
	</term>
	<listitem><para>

		for handling secure http browsing.

	</para></listitem>
	</varlistentry>

	<varlistentry><term><ulink url="ftp://arcana.linux.it/pub/gpm/">GPM (General Purpose Mouse)</ulink></term>
	<listitem><para>

		for mouse support.

	</para></listitem>
	</varlistentry>

	<varlistentry><term><ulink url="http://www.jclark.com/xml/expat.html">expat (XML Parser Toolkit)</ulink></term>
	<listitem><para>

		needed for XBEL support.

	</para></listitem>
	</varlistentry>
</variablelist>
<para>

	You are also advised to read the <filename>README</filename> and the
	<filename>INSTALL</filename> files distributed with ELinks for further
	up to date info on building and installing.

</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
</chapter>
